Previously on AMC's "The Walking Dead..."
《行尸走肉》前情提要
You told us to get ready to fight
你告诉我们要准备抗争
and I can now.
现在我能了
Maggie said that her people could take care of the Saviors.
玛姬说她的人能搞定救世军
But so far all they've done is put our community at risk.
但他们只是让我们的社区陷入险境
I'm asking you to help convince Ezekiel to attack the Saviors
我想让你们帮我劝以西结攻击救世军
and destroy them.
灭掉他们
We'll win,
我们会胜利的
we need to wait for the right moment.
我们要等待合适的时机
We need you.
我们需要你
m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
原创翻译  双语字幕
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
最新连载海外影视剧下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com 仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
Just checking.
核对下
No! No way in hell.
不  绝对不行
That was not the deal.
协议不是这样的
You people swore you could take the Saviors out,
你们发誓能干掉救世军
and you failed.
你们失败了
So any arrangement we had is now done --
所以我们的协议终结了
null and void.
无效了
We aren't trade partners, we aren't friends,
我们不是贸易伙伴  不是朋友
and we never met.
从未谋面
Hmm?
懂吗
We don't know each other.
我们不认识
I owe you nothing.
我不欠你什么
In fact, you owe me for taking in the refugees,
实际上  你欠我的  因为我收留了难民
at great personal risk.
我个人冒了很大的风险
Oh, you were very brave staying in here
你那时真勇敢  待在这里
while Maggie and Sasha saved this place.
而玛姬和萨沙救了这里
Your courage was inspiring.
你的勇气真是鼓舞人心
Hey, don't you work for me?
你不是为我工作吗
Aren't we friends?
我们不是朋友吗
Gregory, we already started this.
格雷戈里  我们已经开始了
- You started it. - We did.
-是你开始的  -是我们
And we're gonna win.
我们会赢的
These are killers.
这些人是凶手啊
Is this how you want to live?
你就想这样活着吗
Under their thumb, killing your people?
受他们的控制  他们还杀你们的人
S-Sometimes we don't get to choose
有时候我们无法选择
what our life looks like.
生活的方式
Sometimes, Ricky,
有时候  瑞克
you have to count the blessings you have.
你得珍惜眼前的一切
How many people can we spare?
我们能分出多少人
How many people here can fight?
这里有多少人可以战斗
"We"?
我们
I don't even know how many people we have, Margaret.
我都不知道我们有多少人  玛格丽特
And does it even matter?
这重要吗
I mean...
我是说
...w-w-what are you gonna do?
你们想做什么
Start a platoon of sorghum farmers?
组一队种高粱的农民吗
'Cause that's what we got.
因为我们只有这种人
They grow things. They're not gonna want to fight.
他们种庄稼  不想战斗
You're wrong.
你错了
When people have the chance to do the right thing,
当人们有机会做正确的事时
they usually step up.
他们一般会挺身而出
- I mean, people just -- - L-Let me stop you
-人们就  -在你开始唱歌之前
before you break into song, okay?
我先打断你一下  好吗
And, by the way,
顺便说一句
who would train all this cannon fodder?
谁来给这些炮灰训练
- I will. - Give me a week.
-我来  -给我一周时间
Rhetorical, okay?
我是反问  好吗
I don't want to know.
我不想知道
I never want to hear another word about any of it, ever.
我再也不想听到关于此事的半个字
Would we be better off without the Saviors,
没了救世军  我们是不是过得更好
- yes or no? - Yeah. Sure. Okay.
-是或不是  -是  好吧
So, what will you do to fix the problem?
那你要怎么解决问题
I didn't say we had a problem.
我没说过我们有问题
You did.
是你们说的
And what happens outside of my purview
在我管辖范围之外发生的事
is outside of my purview.
与我无关
What the hell, man?
搞什么
You're either with us or you ain't.
你要么站我们这边  要么不站
You're sitting over there talking out of both sides of your mouth.
你坐在那里见风使舵  嘴里没实话
I -- I think I've made my position very clear.
我想我已经说得很清楚了
And I want to thank all of you for not being here today
我想感谢你们所有人今天没有来
and not having this meeting with me
没跟我会面
or -- or being seen on your way out.
出去时也别让人看见了
In other words, go out the back.
换句话说  从后门走
- Walking ballsack. - ?Wanna knock that idiot's teeth out.
-懦夫  -真想打掉那蠢货的牙齿
Yeah, well, we don't need him anyway.
反正我们也不需要他
Yeah, that's right.
没错
'Cause we have Maggie and Sasha and Jesus here.
因为我们有玛姬  萨沙和耶稣
And...
还有
Enid.
伊妮德
- Hey, um -- - What's wrong?
-嗨  -怎么了
Nothing.
没什么
Just...
只是
Come outside.
出来吧
What's going on?
怎么了
So, if you don't remember, I'm Bertie.
如果你不记得了  我是伯蒂
And I owe my life to you all, twice over.
你们救了我两次命
A bunch of us do.
我们许多人都被救过
Enid says that you want Gregory
伊妮德说你们想说服格雷戈里
to get us to fight the Saviors with you.
让我们跟你们一起对抗救世军
Is that true?
这是真的吗
- Yes. ?- Do you think we can win,
-是的  -你觉得我们能赢吗
that we really could beat them?
我们真的能打败他们吗
Us?
我们这种人
I do.
是的
Well, Enid says you could show us the way.
伊妮德说你们能训练我们
- I'm ready. - Me too.
-我准备好了  -我也是
-Yeah. -Let's do this.
-是啊  -开始吧
- Let's do it. - I'm in.
-开始吧  -我加入
- It's a start. - We'll get more.
-这是个开始  -我们会找到更多人
- It still won't be enough. - No, it won't.
-还是不够  -是啊
Well, we find the right stuff,
只要找到合适的东西
then maybe we don't need the numbers.
也许根本不需要以人数取胜
Blow 'em up, burn 'em to the ground.
炸飞他们  烧死他们
You said there weren't just soldiers with the Saviors,
你说过救世军里不仅有士兵
that there were workers there.
还有工人
People didn't have a choice.
别无选择的人们
We gotta win.
我们必须赢
We need more hands, another group.
我们需要更多人手  另一个社区
Negan has outposts.
尼根有前哨站
The geography, the distance works against us.
地形和距离都对我们不利
We gotta get back.
我们得回去
If they come looking for Daryl, we need to be there.
如果他们来找达里尔  我们得在
You don't have to get back.
你们没必要回去
Not yet.
现在没必要
It's one of theirs, long range.
这是他们的长距离对讲机
We can listen in, keep track of them.
我们可以偷听  了解他们的动态
So, if we're not going back, what are we doing, then?
如果我们不回去  那我们做什么
I think it's time we introduced you to Ezekiel.
是时候让你们见以西结了
King Ezekiel.
以西结国王
King?
国王
It's called "The Kingdom"?
那里叫神之国吗
Yeah.
是啊
I didn't name it.
名不是我取的
How much farther?
还有多远
Well, technically, we're already here.
严格说来  我们已经到了
I mean, we're always here,
我是说  我们一直在这里
but here we are -- at the Kingdom.
但我们到了  神之国
Well, its outer edge.
这里是它的外围
Hey, what the hell we waitin' on?
我们等什么呢
Waiting for them.
等他们
Who dares to trespass on the sovereign land of the --
何人胆敢擅闯神之国领土...
Oh, shit.
靠
Jesus, is that you?
耶稣  是你吗
Who are all these people, Paul?
这些人是谁  保罗
Hi, Richard.
你好呀  理查德
Nice to see you.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you, too.
我也很高兴见到你
Your friends, who are they?
你的这些朋友们是什么人
This is Rick Grimes.
这位是瑞克・格兰姆斯
He's the leader of a like-minded community.
他是一个和我们志同道合的社区的首领
These are some of his people.
这些是他的一部分人马
We would like to request an audience with King Ezekiel.
我们想觐见以西结国王
Get out of the car.
下车
You say they're a... like-minded community.
你说他们是...志同道合的社区
Like-minded how?
怎么个志同道合法
We live, we trade, we fight the dead.
我们求生  做交易  和行尸战斗
Sometimes others.
有时也和别的东西战斗
Line up.
排好队
Okay. This is a waste of time.
行了  这就是在浪费时间
Come on. Let's go.
走吧  我们回去
Maybe you're right.
也许你说得对
The King is a busy man.
国王很繁忙
And it's a dangerous world.
而这又是个危机四伏的世界
We don't usually allow a pack of strangers
我们一般不会让一群陌生人
to waltz through our door.
随意迈进我们的大门
We want to make the world less dangerous,
我们想让这个世界不那么危机四伏
and we are all here to show the King
我们都是过来向国王表明
how serious we are about that.
我们的认真程度的
The car stays outside.
把车留在外面
You gotta hand over your guns.
枪支上缴
We only have two.
我们就两把枪
Okay.
好了
Follow me.
跟我来
Before we go in,
进去之前我想说
you have a brain and a backbone,
你有勇有谋
so I'm talking to you, not Gregory.
所以我和你谈  而不是格雷戈里
Whatever you're trying to start here,
无论你这次来是为了什么
another protection pact, a trade,
为了另一条庇护协议  或是交易
none of it matters
但这些都毫无意义
if we don't start dealing with the real problem --
除非我们着手处理真正的问题...
the Saviors.
救世军
You know, Richard, I've never seen you smile.
理查德  我从来没见你笑过
I think that's gonna change today.
这一点今天可能要改变了
They have the numbers.
他们人数是挺多的
But can they fight?
但他们能战斗吗
Oh, they can fight.
妥妥的
Maybe.
也许吧
Morgan?
摩根
How do you know each other?
你们是怎么认识的
We go back to the start.
灾变刚开始我们就认识了
Well, the King is ready to see you.
国王准备好接见你们了
- Did you find Carol? - I did, yeah.
-你找到卡萝尔了吗  -找到了
Where is she? Is she okay?
她人呢  她没出事吧
She was here, and then she left.
她之前在这里  后来离开了
You know, she wasn't too happy, me following her.
她不满我跟着她
She wanted to get away from us, from everyone.
她想远离我们  远离所有人
But when I found her, she was shot.
但我找到她时  她中枪了
It was just a graze. I got her back here.
只是擦伤  我把她带回了这里
They got doctors. They're good.
这里有医生  挺厉害的
Was it them?
是他们干的吗
It was.
是的
She had crossed with some of them,
她与他们中几人发生了冲突
and one of them followed her, tried to kill her,
然后其中一个跟着她  想要杀了她
but I stopped him.
但我阻止了他
I killed him.
我杀了他
I had to.
我必须这么做
Carol was here.
卡萝尔之前在这里的
She got help.
她得到了帮助
Now she's gone.
如今她离开了
Jesus!
耶稣
It pleases me to see you, old friend.
很高兴见到你  老朋友
- It pleases him, indeed! - Jerry.
-他确实很高兴  -杰瑞
Tell me,
告诉我
what news do you bring good King Ezekiel?
你给好国王以西结带来了什么消息
Are these new allies you've brought me?
这些你是给我带来的新盟友吗
Indeed, they are, Your Majesty.
确实是的  陛下
This is...
这位是...
Oh, right. I forgot to mention that --
对了  我忘了和你们说...
Yeah, a tiger.
对  有只老虎
This is Rick Grimes,
这位是瑞克・格兰姆斯
the leader of Alexandria,
亚历山大的首领
and these are some of his people.
这些是他的一部分人马
I welcome you all to the Kingdom, good travelers.
欢迎各位来到神之国  旅人们
Now, what brings you to our fair land?
你们为何来到我们美丽的国土
Why do you seek an audience with the King?
你们为何求见本王
Ezekiel --
以西结...
King...Ezekiel.
以西结...国王
Alexandria,
亚历山大
the Hilltop,
山顶寨
and the Kingdom --
神之国...
all three of our communities have something in common.
我们这三个社区有一个共同点
We all serve the Saviors.
我们都供奉救世军
Alexandria already fought them once,
亚历山大曾和他们干过一架
and we won.
我们赢了
We thought we took out the threat,
我们以为自己解决了威胁
but we don't know then what we know now.
但我们那时没有摸清敌情
We only beat one outpost.
我们只是端掉了一个哨站
We've been told you have a deal with them,
我们得知你和他们做了交易
that you know them.
你了解他们
Then you know
那你一定知道
they rule through violence and fear.
他们是用暴力和恐惧进行统治的
Your Majesty, I only told them of the --
陛下  我只告诉了他们...
Our deal with the Saviors is not known among my people --
我的人民并不知道我们和救世军的交易...
for good cause.
这是有正当理由的
We made you a party to that secret
因为你和我们说了山顶寨所受的苦
when you told us of the Hilltop's own travails,
我们才向你透露了那个秘密
but we did not expect you to share --
但我们没想到你会向别人泄密...
We can help each other.
我们可以互相帮助
Don't interrupt the King.
不准打断国王
We brought you into our confidence.
我们信任你
Why did you break it?
你为何要破坏这份信任
Because I want you to hear Rick's plans.
因为我想让你听听瑞克的计划
And what plans have you,
你有何计划呢
Rick Grimes of Alexandria?
亚历山大的瑞克・格兰姆斯
We came to ask the Kingdom, to ask you,
我们来此请求神之国  请求你
to join us in fighting the Saviors,
加入我们  一起反抗救世军
fighting for freedom for all of us.
为所有人的自由而战
What you are asking is very serious.
你的请求很危险
Several of our people -- good people...
我们有好几个人  他们都是好人
were killed by the Saviors, brutally.
被救世军残忍杀害了
Who?
谁
Abraham.
亚伯拉罕
Glenn.
格伦
Spencer, Olivia.
斯宾塞  奥利维亚
Eugene was taken.
尤金被劫走了
They took Daryl.
他们也劫持过达里尔
He escaped.
他逃了出来
Every second he's out here, he's a target.
只要他没被抓回去  他就是个目标
You gonna say you were right?
你想说自己是对的吗
No.
不
I'm...
我
I'm just real sorry they're gone.
他们的死  我非常遗憾
Negan murdered Glenn and Abraham,
尼根杀害了格伦和亚伯拉罕
beat them to death.
活活砸死了他们
Terrorized the Hilltop,
恐吓山顶寨
set loose walkers just to make a point.
放出行尸  只为立威
I used to think the deal was something we could live with.
我曾以为我们能忍受他们的协议
A lot of us did.
很多人都这样以为
But that's changing.
但情况变了
So let's change the world, Your Majesty.
所以让我们改变世界吧  陛下
I want to be honest about what we're asking.
我想坦白说出我们的请求
My people are strong, but there's not enough of us.
我的人很强  但人手不够
We don't have guns... not enough, at least.
我们没枪  至少不够
Not a lot of weapons, period.
没有足够的武器  就这样
We have people.
我们有人手
And weapons.
也有武器
If we strike first, together, we can beat them.
如果我们联盟  先下手为强  就能打败他们
Your Majesty,
陛下
no more waiting for things to get worse
不要再等着事情发展到
beyond what we can handle.
不可收拾的地步了
We set things right.
我们要扭转事态
The time is now.
时机正好
Morgan, what say you?
摩根  你怎么看
Me?
我
Speak.
说吧
People will die.
会死人
A lot of people, and not just the Saviors. It...
会死很多人  不仅是救世军  还有...
If we can find another way,
如果能找到更好的办法
we have to.
必须找到
Maybe it's just about Negan...
也许只是尼根的问题
just capturing him, holding him.
只要抓住他  扣住他
Maybe...
也许
I...
我
The hour grows late.
时候不早了
Rick Grimes of Alexandria...
亚历山大的瑞克・格兰姆斯
you have given the King much to ponder.
国王要深思你的话
Well, when I was a kid,
在我小时候
my mother told me a story.
妈妈给我讲过一个故事
There was a road to a kingdom,
从前有条通向王国的路
and there was a rock in the road.
路中间嵌着一块大石头
And people would just avoid it,
人们只是绕着它走
but horses would break their legs on it and die,
而马匹会被绊到  伤到腿而死
wagon wheels would come off.
马车轮子会脱落
People would lose the goods they'd be coming to sell.
人们损失了很多要卖的货物
That's what happened to a little girl.
一个小女孩就遇到了这种事
The cask of beer her family brewed fell right off.
她自家酿的啤酒桶掉了下来
It broke.
摔坏了
Dirt soaked it all up, and it was gone.
酒都渗进土里  没了
That was her family's last chance.
那是她家最后的指望
They were hungry. They didn't have any money.
他们挨饿  没钱买吃的
She just... sat there and cried, but...
她只能坐在那里哭  但是
...she wondered why it was still there...
她不明白为什么石头还在那
for it to hurt someone else.
伤害着其他人
So she dug at that rock in the road with her hands till they bled,
所以她用双手去挖石头  直到血流不止
used everything she had to pull it out.
用尽力气把它搬了出来
It took hours.
花了好几个小时
And then...
然后
...when she was gonna fill it up,
当她准备填坑的时候
she saw something in it.
她看到坑里有东西
It was a bag of gold.
是一袋金子
All right.
真好
The king had put that rock in the road
是国王埋下的那块石头
because he knew the person who dug it out,
因为他知道  肯挖出它的人
who did something,
肯动手的人
they deserved a reward.
他们值得受奖
They deserved to have their life
他们值得过上
changed for the good.... forever.
更好的生活  直到永远
I invite you all to sup with us
我邀请你们共进晚餐
and stay till the morrow.
并留宿到明天
Yeah, we need to get back home.
我们得回去
I shall deliver my decree in the morn.
清晨我会降旨
Sorry.
抱歉
I...
我
I thought you were one of the dead.
我以为是行尸
Why didn't you just run the other way?
你为什么不掉头跑掉
Well, I'm...I'm training.
我  我在训练
I'm pushing myself,
逼迫自己
trying to step up.
直面困难
Put the safety back on.
把保险上好
Practicing shooting.
我在练习射击
Let me give you some advice.
给你点建议
It's gonna be dark soon.
天快黑了
Don't wander around out here on your own.
别一个人溜达
You'll get yourself killed.
会没命的
Same goes for you, too, right?
你也不该转悠  不是吗
You're not me.
你不是我
Go home, Benjamin.
回家吧  本杰明
- Well, I...Wha...  - ?What?
-那个  我  -什么
Ezekiel's gonna keep coming out here to check on you.
以西结会时常来看望你
He doesn't want to bug you,
他不想打扰你
but he needs to know that you're okay.
但他得知道你是否还好
He told you that?
他跟你说的吗
No.
不是
But I know him.
但我了解他
Well, tell him...
那就告诉他...
I can't.
我不能
He looks out for the people that he cares about.
他对在意的人都会照料倍至
Do you want some food?
你想要吃的吗
A bottle of water?
或者水
I carry extra in case I run into someone who needs it.
我多带了一些以防碰到有需要的人
Why?
为什么
There's not a lot of us left.
因为人已经所剩不多了
Have to help each other.
得互相帮助
Maybe I'll see you again.
或许还会再见到你
Maybe.
或许吧
Heel-toe, heel-toe out here.
在外面脚步要轻
Bend at your knees.
膝盖弯着走
You want to keep quiet.
你得安静点
I heard you from a mile away.
老远就听到你了
Okay.
好
And when this happens,
待一切开始时
and when we allow freedom to ring...
待自由之声响起时
when we let it ring from every village and every hamlet,
响彻每个村庄  每个小镇
from every state and every city,
每个州  每个城市时
we will be able to speed up that day
我们将能加速那一天的到来
when all of God's children,
那时  上帝的所有子民
black men and white men,
黑人和白人
Jews and Gentiles, Protestants and Catholics,
犹太人和非犹太人  新教徒和天主教徒
will be able to join hands
能携手并进
and sing in the words of the old Negro spiritual --
合唱那首古老的黑人灵歌
Free at last, Free at last!
终于自由了  终于自由了
Thank God Almighty,
感谢全能的上帝
we are...free at last.
我们...终于自由了
Thanks for stepping in on story duty.
谢谢你今天来帮我讲故事
I stopped in to say good night.
我来道晚安
You missed supper. Where were you?
你没来吃晚餐  你去哪了
Went for a walk in the woods.
去林子里散了散步
You went out there?
你出去了
- Unaccompanied? - ?Yeah.
-没人陪同吗  -是的
Took out two dead ones on my way back.
回来的路上干掉了两个行尸
Getting pretty good with the stick.
棍子使得不错了
Wanted to practice with the gun.
想练练枪法
I, saw Carol out there.
我看到卡萝尔在外面
Did she, uh...seem well?
她看起来还好吗
- Did -- Did you talk to her? ?- Yeah.
-你跟她说话了吗  -说了
She asked why I carry food and water
她问我为什么带着食物和水
in case I run into people.
以防遇到别人
And you told her?
你告诉她了吗
It's the same reason we should say yes to Rick.
那也是为什么我们该答应瑞克
Elaborate.
说来听听
You saw their eyes.
你看到了他们的眼神
They're gonna risk everything if we help them or not.
有没有我们的帮助  他们都会搏命的
And if we don't help them, if we turn away,
如果我们不帮他们  对他们置之不理
then they can't win.
他们就赢不了
And if they do, somehow...
假设他们赢了
they will have saved us,
他们就救了我们
and we won't have done a thing.
我们什么也不用干
My dad always said
我爸爸常说
that if you're asked to be the hero,
要是有人让你去逞英雄
be a hero.
那就去逞
You wanted me to be ready for anything, and I am.
你想让我对一切都做好准备  我准备好了
We are.
我们准备好了
I thank you for your sage counsel.
感谢你的建议
Your father would be very proud.
你父亲会非常骄傲的
The King is very proud.
国王很骄傲
This is life here.
这就是这里的生活
Every day.
每一天
But it came at a cost.
但这是有代价的
And I wanted more of this.
我曾想要更多
I wanted to expand.
我曾想要扩张
To create more places like this.
建造更多像这里一样的地方
Men and women lost their limbs.
人们失去了四肢
Children lost their parents
孩子们失去了双亲
because I sent them into battle against the wasted
因为我在没必要的时候
when I did not need to.
派他们去与行尸作战
This is different.
这次不同
It isn't.
并不是
The dead don't rule us.
行尸不会统治支配我们
The world doesn't look like this outside your walls.
外面的世界跟墙内截然不同
People don't have it as good.
人们过得没这么好
Some people don't have it good at all.
有些人过得凄惨之至
I have to worry about my people.
我只能为我的子民考虑
You call yourself a damn king.
你称自己为国王
You sure as hell don't act like one.
却一点没有国王的样子
All of this...
这一切
came at a cost.
都有代价
It was lives, arms, legs.
是用生命  残肢断臂换来的
The peace we have with the Saviors is uneasy,
和救世军的和平并不稳定
but it is peace.
但起码是和平
I have to hold on to it.
我得把握住
I have to try.
我得尝试
Although the Kingdom cannot grant you the aid you desire,
尽管神之国不能提供你们需要的协助
the King is sympathetic to your plight.
但国王同情你的困境
I offer our friend Daryl asylum
我可以为友人达里尔提供庇护
for as long as he requires it.
他想留多久都行
He will be safe here.
他在这里很安全
The Saviors do not set foot inside our walls.
救世军不会进入我们的围墙
How long do you think that's gonna last?
你觉得这种情况能撑多久
I knew what was coming.
我知道会发生什么
I knew that King guy would say no.
我知道那个国王会拒绝
But it still pissed me off.
但我还是很生气
What the hell are you telling me for?
你跟我讲这个干什么
We both had sex with the same dead guy.
我们睡过同一个死人
It doesn't make us friends.
不代表我们是朋友了
You can change his mind, but you won't.
你能改变他的心意  但你不愿这么做
Then you can stay.
那你可以留下来
We can talk.
我们聊聊
How many people do we have?
我们有多少人
To fight?
能战斗的
I'll go with you.
我跟你们走
We don't even have enough
我们连从正面
to take on one outpost face-to-face yet.
攻下一个哨站的人手都不够
So the Kingdom has to get involved,
所以神之国必须加入进来
or the Saviors will always be in charge.
否则救世军会一直掌管一切
It isn't about soldiers.
不是士兵的问题
We're making them stronger.
是我们使他们变得更强
The more food we give them,
给他们的食物越多
the more arms, the more everything,
武器越多  或者任何东西更多
every day any of us give them something,
每天我们中有人给他上贡
they become harder and harder to beat.
他们就会变得越难被打败
All right, open it up. We're gone.
好了  开门  我们走
You're not.
你不能走
I'm not staying here.
我不能留在这
You have to.
你必须留下
It's the smartest play.
这是最聪明的做法
You know it is.
你心里清楚
Try to talk to Ezekiel.
试着跟以西结谈谈
Or stare him into submission --
或者一直盯着他直到他妥协
Whatever it takes.
不管用什么方法
We'll be back soon.
我们很快回来
For anyone out there
致所有
who loved the obese bastard as much as I did,
和我一样爱那个肥鬼的人
I just want to say a few words.
我只想说几句
Fat Joey was not the most badass son of bitch,
肥乔不是最牛逼的那个
but he was loyal.
但是他很忠诚
He had a great sense of humor.
他很幽默
In fact, we were just joking about oral sex
实际上前两天我们还在开玩笑
with Lucille the other day.
和露西尔口交
Things will not be the same now that he's dead.
他死了一切都不一样了
Without Fat Joey,
没了肥乔
Skinny Joey is just Joey.
瘦乔就只是乔了
So it's a goddamn tragedy.
真他妈悲催
So, let's have a moment of silence.
让我们默哀片刻
Someone's trying to block the way.
有人想挡路
Gotta be the Saviors.
肯定是救世军
Look.
看
I think that's their base over there.
我想那是他们的基地
Yeah, that's it.
是的
Must be trying to make it hard to get to them.
一定是想让别人难接近他们
We gotta keep going.
我们得前进
We'll move them, and then we'll move them back.
我们移开车  然后再移回来
They don't need to know we were here.
他们不会知道我们来过
Rick.
瑞克
Come take a look at this.
来看看
What's all this for?
这是为了什么
Wait.
等等
When I was hiding in the back of the truck,
我在卡车后面藏着的时候
I heard a couple of them talking about this.
听到有几个人讨论
This is for a herd.
是为尸群准备的
That's why it's a steel cable.
所以用的是钢索
It's not just for one walker.
不只是为了一只行尸
It's for a lot.
是为很多
We need these explosives.
我们需要这些炸药
Yeah.
是的
But we have to figure out how to disarm it first.
但首先我们得想办法拆除
Okay.
好吧
Backing up is not gonna make a difference
如果这东西爆炸
if this thing goes off.
后退也没用
We got ourselves a red situation.
出现红色事件
I need a search party.
派一支搜索队
See if Daryl ran home like the dumb animal that he is.
看看达里尔有没有犯傻跑回家
On it. Be there in time for lunch.
就去办  午饭前赶到
Turn that sleepy little burg upside down.
把那个小破地儿掘地三尺
We gotta go.
我们该走了
We gotta get there before them, but we need these.
我们得在他们之前回去  但我们需要这些
- We need to clear a path anyway. - Yeah.
-我们得清出一条路  -是
Rosita?
罗西塔
First part's done.
第一部分完成
What now? We gotta unwrap the secondary explosives --
现在呢  我们得拆掉次级炸药
the dynamite, the RPGs.
炸药  火箭筒
Make sure these casings are not messed up,
确保别装混了
and do not mess them up, either.
也不要乱动
This thing could still blow.
这些东西还能炸
You all heard her. Let's go.
都听到了  行动
You can load the explosives into the trunk as long as they're in good shape.
把完好的炸药装上车
No dents, no tears. They're not live.
不能有凹痕和撕裂  它们没激活
They still need to be triggered to be set off.
还需要被触发引爆
Not that one.
别拿这个
- I don't like the way it looks. - Okay.
-看起来不对劲  -好
Dad.
爸
Look.
看
Okay. There they are.
好  它们在那
But they're far.
但还远
We still have time.
我们还有时间
You sure?
确定吗
We need these.
我们需要这些
And we need to get the cars back in front of the onramp.
我们得把车放回斜坡前面
They'll know we took their explosives, so does it matter?
他们会知道我们拿了炸药  有什么用呢
- We want that herd to stay on the highway. - ?Why?
-我们要让尸群留在公路上  -为什么
We may need it.
我们也许会用到
Okay. Tara, Carl, come on!
好了  塔拉  卡尔  快来
Uh...Rick...
瑞克
All right.
好了
Sasha, Jesus,
萨沙  耶稣
can you get back to the Hilltop on foot?
你们可以走回山顶寨吗
Yeah.
可以
Tell Maggie we're not giving up.
告诉玛姬我们不会放弃
Go!
走
Here.
给
We need every stick, every RPG.
我们需要每一根炸药  火箭弹
Yeah.
好
Rick.
瑞克
They're gonna cut them off.
它们会堵死他们
Can we just split up?
我们分头走吧
No.
不行
The cars.
车
If they run...
如果能开动的话...
We lay on the horn when we start it --
我们启动的时候鸣笛
I'll bring my arm down, and we go. ?Yes.
我挥下手一起走  好的
Stay together!
跟上来
- Damn it! ?- We'll figure it out.
-该死  -我们会想办法
Yeah, I didn't like the look of that shit at all.
我就说看起来不对劲
I pushed it.
是我硬要做的
We're here.
我们在这
You can smile.
你可以笑了
We made it.
我们成功了
We can make it.
我们可以做到
We can.
我们可以
We're the ones who live.
我们是活下来的人
Lose the car?
车扔了吗
Uh, it's somewhere safe.
在安全的地方
- You didn't find anything. ?- No.
-你什么都没找到  -没有
Listen, we need to get everyone ready.
听着  我们得让所有人准备好
The--
救...
Rick. Hello.
瑞克  你好
And...hello again.
还有  再次你好
We thought it'd be longer.
想着你们不会这么快来
Do you think we're here for a tribute?
你以为我们来收贡品吗
Do you?
是不是
Is there another reason?
还有别的原因吗
There is.
有
We're here for Daryl.
我们来找达里尔
But Negan took Daryl.
可尼根抓走了达里尔
Oh, but... then your son showed up,
但是你儿子来了
Daryl went missing --
达里尔就失踪了
might those two things be connected?
也许这两件事有关
They're not.
没关
We didn't know he was gone till right now.
我们现在才知道他逃跑了
Then this should be easy.
那就简单了
Now, everyone find a buddy.
现在  每人找一人
Gonna have to follow us around.
跟我们走
If he's here,
如果他在这
we really need you all to see him die.
我们要确保让你们亲眼看他死
Wow.
天啊
These are some bare shelving units.
架子空空如也
You guys have a barbecue or something
你们办了烧烤
and not invite us?
没叫我们吗
Seriously, this is sad.
真的  太悲哀了
Hope you're not trying to hide stuff from us,
希望你们没有藏东西
'cause that generally doesn't go over very well.
因为那通常没好下场
We have a lot of people.
我们人很多
It's...getting harder to find stuff,
找东西越来越难
and our focus lately has been on finding things
我们最近的重心是寻找
that Negan might want.
尼根要的东西
We're still adjusting to the new system.
我们还在适应新体制
We were gonna scavenge more today.
我们今天会找到更多
If you just wait, we'll...bring something back.
如果你愿意等  我们会带东西回来
We'll find more.
我们会找到更多
Relax.
放松
I'm not here for a pick-up.
我不是来收贡的
Good thing.
这是好事
But that day is coming,
但那天快到了
so you best do whatever you need to.
所以你们最好做该做的事
Dig deep.
好好找
Go the extra mile.
加倍努力
Take some risks!
冒一下险
We will.
我们会的
Well, we will appreciate that.
我们会感激的
Thank you for the cooperation, Rick.
感谢你的合作  瑞克
My apologies for leaving the place a bit of a mess,
抱歉把这里搞乱了
but we got a litany of other shit to attend to.
但是我们还有其他屁事要去做
So do you, I guess.
我猜你也是
Tick-tock.
抓紧
Chop-chop.
快点
Oh! And, Rick...
还有  瑞克
if Daryl does turn up here
如果达里尔真在这里出现
two days from now, two months from now...
两天后  两个月后
hell, two years from now,
见鬼  两年后
just know there's no statute of limitations on this.
你要知道这事没有诉讼时效
Keep that hatchet handy.
把斧子放在手边
You're gonna need it if he turns up with you people.
如果他在你们这出现  你会用上的
And it won't turn out the way it did for your boy.
这次可不会像你儿子那次一样了
What happened to the pantry?
储藏室怎么了
We don't know.
不清楚
And we need to talk about Gabriel.
我们得谈谈加百利
Where is he?
他在哪
He was on watch the night you all went to scavenge.
你们去找物资的那晚  他在值班
I was supposed to take over for him in the morning.
我和他本来应该早上换班
He wasn't at his post.
他没在哨岗上
Pantry was cleared out and a car was gone.
储藏室被清空了  少了一辆车
No one's seen him since.
没人再看到过他
That son of a bitch.
那个杂种
- He stole our shit and ran. - ?That's...what it looks like.
-他偷东西跑掉了  -看起来是这样
- Well, I don't want to believe it. - I don't believe it.
-我不想相信  -我不相信
That's not Gabriel.
加百利不是那样的人
He wouldn't do that to us.
他不会那样对我们
I thought he changed, too,
我也以为他变了
but it can't be anything else.
但没有其他可能
Yes, it can.
有的
I can't believe he would just take our stuff and go.
不敢相信他会带我们的东西跑掉
I mean, that's -- that's not who he is.
他不是那样的人
Well, he saw Olivia and Spencer die
他看到奥利维亚和斯宾塞死了
right in front of him.
就在他面前
I know. I just...
我知道  我只是...
He found his courage, you know?
他找到了勇气  知道吗
I want to believe he held on to it.
我真心希望他能坚持住
Why wouldn't he have taken this with him?
他为什么不带走这个
Why would he leave it on the floor?
他为什么丢在地板上
There weren't tracks out there before.
外面没有之前的痕迹
We didn't find anything now.
我们没找到什么
Maybe Daryl could've picked something up.
也许达里尔能发现些什么
He left.
他走了
He didn't leave a note.
没留纸条
He obviously doesn't want to be found.
显然不想被找到
Yes, he does.
他想的
How would he know we were out there?
他怎么知道我们去过那里
I don't know.
我不知道
So that's it?
就这样吗
You're finally leaving me?
你终于要离开我了
You caught me.
被你发现了
I'm just...
我只是
sick of being so damn happy at home, you know?
厌倦了在家里的快乐
Didn't know how to tell you.
不知道该怎么跟你说
Babe --
亲爱的
They need me.
他们需要我
Gabriel needs me.
加百利需要我
If I ask you something,
如果我问你一件事
will you tell me the truth?
你能说实话吗
- Of course. - ?The others didn't go out there scavenging, did they?
-当然  -他们不是出去找物资的  对吧
They're going after them again, and they're not telling us.
他们又要抗击了  而他们没告诉我们
Rick has his reasons.
瑞克有他的理由
Rick didn't get the shit beaten out of him.
瑞克没有被毒打过
You think this is about Gabriel, but it's gonna be more.
你以为这只是去找加百利  但会有更多的事
It's always more.
总会有更多的事
So, please, please don't go.
所以拜托了  别走
Gabriel's one of us.
加百利是我们的一员
I have to.
我必须去
What's going on with the Saviors, that isn't this.
救世军的事  与此无关
If Rick is taking on the Saviors,
如果瑞克要对抗救世军
that is everything.
那一切都有关
W-What if they find out while you're gone?
如果你们不在的时候他们发现了呢
What if they come back here?
如果他们回来呢
Do you want to leave?
你想离开吗
Just turn our backs?
背弃他们吗
I want us alive.
我想要我们活着
Both of us.
两个人都活着